<?xml version="1.0" encoding="iso-8859-1"?>
<feed version="0.3" xmlns="http://purl.org/atom/ns#" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xml:lang="en">
  <title>Bill&apos;s Blog</title>
  <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/" />
  <modified>2017-06-25T18:25:16Z</modified>
  <tagline></tagline>
  <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2018://1</id>
  <generator url="http://www.movabletype.org/" version="2.661">Movable Type</generator>
  <copyright>Copyright (c) 2017, bill</copyright>
  <entry>
    <title>Birthday Party</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000262.html" />
    <modified>2017-06-25T18:25:16Z</modified>
    <issued>2017-06-25T13:25:16-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2017://1.262</id>
    <created>2017-06-25T18:25:16Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain"> Not Too Many Years Back Press HERE to see a slideshow from 40 years ago. Press HERE to see a slideshow of My Baby Pics. Birthday Party Celebrating 70 years of Life To all my friends and family Please,...</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    <dc:subject>Correspondence</dc:subject>
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<div style='float: right; padding: 1em; margin-left: 6pt;'>
<b>Not Too Many Years Back</b><br/>
<img alt='IMG_2822: I am sixty-four'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5261/5894568870_e1f5b307b1.jpg'   width=‘500' height=‘400' /></p>
<p align='center'><b>Press <a href='https://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157630034873785/show/
' target='_blank'>HERE</a> to see a slideshow<br/> from 40 years ago.</b></p>
<p align='center'><b>Press <a href='https://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157619947996458/show/
' target='_blank'>HERE</a> to see a slideshow<br/> of My Baby Pics.</b></p>
</div>
<h1 align='center'>Birthday Party</h1>
<h2 align='center'>Celebrating 70 years of Life</h2>
<h3 align='center'>To all my friends and family</br>
Please, join us on the 8th of July</h3>
<p>
I will be 70 years-old in July.  It has been 10 years since my last birthday party. The time has come for old friends to gather on a hot summer day. Bring a friend and your families. This grandfather loves children and they will be welcome.  So join the celebration.  </p>
<h3>Details -</h3>
<p><u>
Where</u>: </br>
Our backyard at <b>the Elliot Avenue house in Bloomington</b>. </p>
<p><u>
When</u>:</br>
<b>Saturday, the 8th of July from 5 to 11 pm</b>. </p>
<p><u>
Refreshments</u>:</br>
We will have soft drinks, beer, wine and some stronger spirits.</br>
Or bring your favorite beverage or something special to share.</br>
<p><u>
Food</u>:</br>
We will have <b>Mexican</b> food for all.</br>
You are welcome to bring a dish or dessert. If you do, please, contact Betty. </p>
<p><u>
History</u>:</br>
From my 20th to my 60th annual birthday party, the infamous celebration led to much fun.</br>
Do you remember that special birthday cake from my 30th, or the roasted pig from my 60th.</br>
Bring a story from a bygone party, a memory to share.  And let us create a new memory on the 8th of July.  </p>
<p>
Do you want to <b>PRINT</b> this invitation?</br>
Then <b>Press <a href='http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/70thBdayInvite.pdf' target='_blank'>HERE</a></b> to load a printable pdf file.</p>]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bernie Sanders on Rising Wealth Inequality</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000261.html" />
    <modified>2017-04-24T18:29:18Z</modified>
    <issued>2017-04-24T13:29:18-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2017://1.261</id>
    <created>2017-04-24T18:29:18Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain">In nearly every speech presented by Senator Bernie Sanders in the past thirty years, he has mentioned the shame of growing wealth inequality. Here is why it has been central to his sense of fairness and justice. Let us start...</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    <dc:subject>Politics</dc:subject>
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<p>In nearly every speech presented by Senator Bernie Sanders in the past thirty years, he has mentioned the shame of growing wealth inequality. Here is why it has been central to his sense of fairness and justice. </p>
<p>Let us start by understanding what wealth is.  Popular definitions usually refer to a large accumulation of money as wealth.  This definition makes clear how wealth is measured but does not really go far enough.  The early economist Adam Smith in his book <i>The Wealth of Nations</i> defined  wealth as "the annual produce of the land and labour of the society". This "produce" is, at its simplest, that which satisfies human needs and wants of utility. </p>
<p>Wealth is what our society, and every other society, produces when it creates the things that are needed and wanted by the people.  </p>
<p>Here is the critical question:  “Who creates the things that we need and want to use, who creates the wealth?” If you get up and go to work on a regular basis, all you need to do is look around at your co-workers.  You can see the wealth of the nation being created before you very eyes.  Clearly, people who work create all wealth.</p>
<p>Under the capitalist economic system, the producer of wealth, the worker, does not have the right to retain the full value of his labor.  The capitalist class gets to keep the lion’s share of the wealth produced.  Forty years ago, workers could keep the wealth that they produced in first four to six hours of their day. Today, they only get to keep the wealth that they produce in the first two to three hours of work.  So, in forty years, the share taken by the super-rich capitalists has almost doubled.  How can that be?  Modern technology has double the productivity of the American worker.  In the years before that, workers shared in their rising productivity with rising incomes and happier, healthier lives. </p>
<p>Wealth inequality is at the basis for the inherent unfairness of the capitalist system. Rising wealth inequality is a symptom of growing unfairness in our economic system.  Bernie Sanders would like to see the growing inequality end.  Had the share that the capitalist class takes remained constant over the past forty years, real wages would have nearly doubled.  How much better off would Americans be today if that were the case?</p>
<p>There are many ways to begin reversing growing wealth inequality.  None will be simple institute.  Nearly every program called for by Senator Sanders would start to shift the balance back toward the average working person.</p>
<p>In summary, wealth is created by working people.  The super-rich capitalists take the lion’s share of the wealth and leaving the working people poorer for their effort. Wealth inequality is an inherent to capitalist economic system, and it is the basis for system’s  unfairness.</p>]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Bologna</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000260.html" />
    <modified>2016-11-05T13:21:15Z</modified>
    <issued>2016-11-05T08:21:15-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2016://1.260</id>
    <created>2016-11-05T13:21:15Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain"> Press HERE to see a slideshow of Bologna (70+ photos). Basilica of St. Petronius Boys in Piazza of Saint Stefano Lion at Duomo of Modena This is the least interesting of the cities that we have visited during this...</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    <dc:subject>Travel Journal</dc:subject>
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<div style='float: right; padding: 1em; margin-left: 6pt;'>
<p align='center'><b>Press <a href='https://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157676078787355/show/' target='_blank'>HERE</a> to see a slideshow<br/> of Bologna (70+ photos).</b></p>
<table border = '0' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b>Basilica of St. Petronius</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5340/30662044951_8a6bb0468f_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Basilica of St. Petronius IMG_1157'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5340/30662044951_8a6bb0468f_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Boys in Piazza of Saint Stefano</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5685/30662042361_da1f628efc_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Piazza of Saint Stefano IMG_1169'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5685/30662042361_da1f628efc_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Lion at Duomo of Modena</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5800/30449948140_97d7c3c15c_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Duomo IMG_1199'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5800/30449948140_97d7c3c15c_m.jpg'   width='240' height='180'  /></a></td> </tr>
</tbody> </table>
</div>
<p>
This is the least interesting of the cities that we have visited during this journey around the Adriatic Sea.  Still Bologna offered one of the largest and most beautiful churches, the Basilica of St. Petronius.  Of course, our feelings about this may have something to do with the weather, which has been cool and most overcast.  The weather could best described as dreary.</p>
<p>
There are several spectacular churches here, and we visited them along with a few smaller churches.  The only other places of great interest were a very old library and two tall towers.   </p>
<div style='float: left; padding: 1em; margin-right : 6pt;  '>
<p align='center'> <b>Street Musicians Mata Bicho</b> <br />
<iframe width="480" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/WlCNGfIOrLw" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>
</div><p>
We have heard some good street musicians.  One day, there was some sort of soapbox speaker in the main square.  </p>
<p>
We did have one very sunny and fairly warm day on Wednesday.  On that day we traveled to Modena.  Modena is a small city that once rivaled the much larger city of Bologna.  While smaller, it seemed brighter (well the sun was out) and it was a lot cleaner. We found some nice squares and a fantastic Duomo with its huge tower.  There was a wonderful covered market where one could find all sorts of foods, from vegetables to fish to cheese and to meat. At the market visited a vendor of cheese and vinegar. Of course I mean Parmigiano-Reggiano cheese and Balsamico di Modena vinegar. He explained the difference in the products and had us taste the 12, 24 and 36 month cheese and three or four vinegars. They were amazing. We dropped a few Euros at his shop.  </p>
<p>
There are a lot of photos so be sure to view the slide show.  </p>
<p>
We will be flying back to the USA on Sunday, where we have heard that they are experiencing the nicest autumn in many years and a truly lovely election experience. It will be great to be home.  </p>
<p align='center' >
<b>Bill and Betty in Modena<br/>
   Eating a Lunch of Cheese, Olives and Bread</b><br/>
<img alt='Bill and Betty IMG_1753'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5544/30449943840_03d7808c38_c.jpg'   width='800' height='450' /></p>  
]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ravenna</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000259.html" />
    <modified>2016-10-29T18:37:49Z</modified>
    <issued>2016-10-29T13:37:49-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2016://1.259</id>
    <created>2016-10-29T18:37:49Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain"> Press HERE to see a slideshow of Ravenna (50+ photos). Mosaic Couch along the Channel Mosaic Ceiling-Baptistery of Ariani Mausoleum of Theodoric Last Sunday we traveled to Ravenna by train. We walked a half-mile to an apartment we had...</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    <dc:subject>Travel Journal</dc:subject>
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<div style='float: right; padding: 1em; margin-left: 6pt;'>
<p align='center'><b>Press <a href='https://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157674306835392/show/' target='_blank'>HERE</a> to see a slideshow<br/> of Ravenna (50+ photos).</b></p>
<table border = '0' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b> Mosaic Couch along the Channel</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5808/30584470986_cfc32a2960_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Mosaic Couch on the Marina Channel IMG_1148'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5808/30584470986_cfc32a2960_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Mosaic Ceiling-Baptistery of Ariani</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8637/30278811220_fe232f4719_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='The Baptistery of Ariani IMG_1088'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8637/30278811220_fe232f4719_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Mausoleum of Theodoric</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5466/30620601695_52472bdf3c_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Mausoleum of Theodoric IMG_1147'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5466/30620601695_52472bdf3c_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>

</tbody> </table>
</div>

<p>
Last Sunday we traveled to Ravenna by train.  We walked a half-mile to an apartment we had rented for the week.  I think it is the nicest apartment so far and the least expensive in Italy.  We quickly got settled. Our last apartment in Verona had no washing machine, so the first thing we did was wash clothes.  For Americans you should know that clothes dryers really don't exist in most places outside the USA.  So, we put them on a drying rack.  Due to overcast and cool temperatures they had to dry inside for several days. </p>
<p>
Like I said, it was cool and overcast from Sunday to Wednesday.  Still we walked to the center on Monday.  The local information office provided us with a lot of useful information.  We did not do much more on Monday.  We visited the tomb of Dante.  Yes, after Dante was exiled from Florence, this was his home ground.  He was buried here and Florence has been trying to get his remains back ever since. We had lunch in a cafeteria.  Then we visited a large, local, active church.  <b>Ravenna is world famous for the mosaics found in its churches</b>.  This church had a large number of pieces that had been moved to the church.  They were all very good  </p>
<p>
Tuesday, we started by heading to the Tomb of Theodoric.  As we made our way in that direction we passed by a large, old military fortress that had been turned into a city park.  It was really very cool.  We decided to skip the tomb and go to the Basilica of Saint Vitale and the Mausoleum of Galla Placidia.  Here we found the most astounding mosaics on the floors, walls and ceilings. When you see the pictures, keep on telling yourself "These are mosaic and not paintings."  And they are from the 5th and 6th century. We did a bit more walking where we were checking out some small churches and the courtyards that every Italian block has hidden behind their buildings. We tried a bit of the local specialty, cappeletti with ragu. So, tasty! Finally we went to a concert in a local theater.  We think they were older students from a local university, but that is not for sure.  Betty recorded one of the movements that they played from the Symphony in D major by Haydn and Solomon, which was the better of the two recordings.  She also got two minutes from the Kegelstatt Trio (W. A. Mozart).
Here are links to two recordings of what we heard.  This <a href='http://sundstrom.us/audio/Ravenna Concert Haydn-Salomon London.mp3' target='_blank' ><b>link</b></a> was the better piece.  And here is a link  <a href='http://sundstrom.us/audio/Ravenna Concert Motzart Kegelstatt Trio.mp3' target='_blank' ><b>link</b></a> to the other.  Please give a listen to them.     </p>
<div style='float: left; padding: 1em; margin-right : 6pt;  '>
<p align='center'> <b>Tugs Pulling Freighter</b> <br />
<iframe width="480" height="270" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/CfYCnRXaIcA" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>
</div><p>
We really took Wednesday off, which was another cool overcast day.  So, I will move on to warm and sunny Thursday. We visit a few more places in the center.  We visited the Duomo of Ravenna.  The Duomo was completed in the early 1700's.  Then we visited the very old Neonian Baptistery, called the Baptistery Deli Ortodossi.  Again the Mosaics were spectacular.  We also visited a museum, whose contents mainly came from a church that collapsed three hundred years ago.  After lunch we finally walked to the Tomb of Theodoric.  The tomb is in a large public park so we took a break to rest and watch children enjoying the playground equipment.  </p>
<p>
Friday we did a day trip to Marina di Ravenna.  This is a port about six miles from Ravenna that serves the city and the region around Ravenna.  We took a walk in the woods.  There was a problem with the trail.  It was fenced so we could not cross to the main road unless we hiked to the next town.  We had planned to go to a restaurant on the main road that was no more than 300 meters on the other side of the very high fence.  Finally we came to an area that opened up into the woods.  We headed toward the main road only to find backyard fences.  Luckily one was low enough for us to get over it.  We walked through their carport to a front yard gate.  No, it would not open.  So, up and over we went.  Five minutes later we were on the main road and 100 meters from our restaurant.  We ate a nice lunch and took the bus back to Ravenna.</p>
<p align='center' >
<b>Large Mosaic at Basilica of San Vitale</b><br/>
<img alt='Basilica of San Vitale IMG_1633'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5350/29946431824_0355da636c_b.jpg'   width='1000' height='750' /></p>]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Verona</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000258.html" />
    <modified>2016-10-22T09:58:04Z</modified>
    <issued>2016-10-22T04:58:04-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2016://1.258</id>
    <created>2016-10-22T09:58:04Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain"> Press HERE to see a slideshow of Verona (80+ photos). The Arena Church of Santa Anastasia Outside Castelvecchio In case you forgot, Verona is the place where Romeo and Juliet met, fell in love, and died. Perhaps that is...</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<div style='float: right; padding: 1em; margin-left: 6pt;'>
<p align='center'><b>Press <a href='https://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157671990333563/show/' target='_blank'>HERE</a> to see a slideshow<br/> of Verona (80+ photos).</b></p>
<table border = '0' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b>The Arena</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5820/30447478766_7e66c98f0e_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='The Arena IMG_0932'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5820/30447478766_7e66c98f0e_m.jpg'   width='240' height='180'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Church of Santa Anastasia</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5817/29851451153_9869d5fdf1_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Church of Santa Anastasia IMG_0967'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5817/29851451153_9869d5fdf1_m.jpg'   width='240' height='180'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Outside Castelvecchio</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5727/29851383873_4532072390_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Outside Castelvecchio IMG_1014'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5727/29851383873_4532072390_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
</tbody> </table>
</div>
<p>
In case you forgot, Verona is the place where Romeo and Juliet met, fell in love, and died.  Perhaps that is why it has become such an important tourist attraction.  The large number of tourists, mostly Germans, totally surprised us.  </p>
<p>
We arrived on Sunday afternoon and made our way to a nice one-bedroom apartment.  It has ended up being our most expensive booking on AirBnB, but given the popularity of Verona it was the best we could do.  The manager of the flat was the Truly Agency.  They were not totally prepared for us.  We make it clear that we MUST have broadband internet.  Once again there were problems, which were temporarily resolved the next day. Then the problem re-emerged and their solution was to move us to a different apartment.  I use the word "move" rather loosely, we packed our own things, had to move food we had gotten for the week, then walked almost one mile to the agency, then another quarter-mile to the new apartment. Since then the place has been fine with a great internet connection. </p>
<div style='float: left; padding: 1em; margin-right : 6pt;  '>
<table border = '0' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b>Castle Scaligero in Sirmione</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5719/30447586036_7f80c01d7a_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Castle Scaligero IMG_1071'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5719/30447586036_7f80c01d7a_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b>Bill in Sirmione</b> <br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5338/30483926475_78a80791d1_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Bill in Sirmione IMG_1607'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5338/30483926475_78a80791d1_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
</tbody> </table>
</div>
<p>
We started with a visit to the city's central square, Piazza Bra, which has a Roman arena in the square. The next day we returned to the Piazza Bra.  From there we walked to Piazza Erbe and on to the first of many churches.  This one was the Duomo Cathedral of Santa Maria Matriculate.  Before our week ended we visited many more. The best was the Church of Santa Anastasia.  You will want to see our many photos of the churches.</p>
<p>
One day we went to the Castelvecchio. Historically, the castle was mainly a military compound.  Today, it is museum full of old, fairly uninteresting religious art.  But the castle itself is beautiful with many battlements with crenellation.  From the castle emerges a bridge of similar architectural forms that crossed the River Adige. </p>
<p>
Yesterday, we took a day trip to Sirmione.  Sirmione is on Lake Garda.  We had heard that it was a popular place.  We wrongly assumed that this would be a quiet little village with a few tourists.  There were more than two thousand in a fairly small place.  The area is thick with hotels and restaurants.  We explored the peninsula for a few hours then stopped for a delightful lunch. I had several perch fillets from Lake Garda and Betty had a beautiful plate of lasagna.  By the way, in Italy all sit-down restaurants have a cover charge of $2 to $4 per person.  That means one does not stop for a coffee or even a beer, unless you plan on eating and drinking a lot.  We have seen this from time-to-time in other places, but we always find the practice disgusting.  </p>
<p>
Tomorrow we will travel to Ravenna.  You can expect a posting from Ravenna in a week.  </p>
<p align='center' >
<b>Along the River Adige</b><br/>
<img alt='Along the River Adige IMG_0930'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5503/30483848805_f97f2eff1c_b.jpg'   width='1024' height='576' /></p>  ]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Venice</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000257.html" />
    <modified>2016-10-18T15:29:51Z</modified>
    <issued>2016-10-18T10:29:51-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2016://1.257</id>
    <created>2016-10-18T15:29:51Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain"> Press HERE to see a slideshow of Venice (90+ photos). Bill Over the Grand Canal Betty on the Riva Another Canal We traveled by train to the Mestre Station. I just want to rave about the Italian Train System....</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    <dc:subject>Travel Journal</dc:subject>
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<div style='float: right; padding: 1em; margin-left: 6pt;'>
<p align='center'><b>Press <a href='https://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157675366820675/show/' target='_blank'>HERE</a> to see a slideshow<br/> of Venice (90+ photos).</b></p>
<table border = '0' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b>Bill Over the Grand Canal</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8274/30107401210_85de25d294_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Bill Over the Grand Canal IMG_1514'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8274/30107401210_85de25d294_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Betty on the Riva</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5760/29773858474_320d8953c4_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Betty on the Riva IMG_1564'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5760/29773858474_320d8953c4_m.jpg'   width='240' height='180'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Another Canal</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8639/29772382233_b20e34a0be_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Canal IMG_0867'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8639/29772382233_b20e34a0be_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
</tbody> </table>
</div>
<p>
We traveled by train to the Mestre Station.  I just want to rave about the Italian Train System.  The system runs on time, is not expensive costing less than buses.  Even stopping at many small cities, the time from Trieste to Mestre was less than two hours.  We will use the trains through out our Italian journey.  </p>
<p>
We booked a room in Mestre for three nights. Mestre was once a separate town, but is now a large, on-land neighborhood of Venice. The room was nothing fancy but adequate with a private bath.  The B&B provided something of a breakfast.  We arrived on Thursday morning.  We took the bus into the old city that everyone knows as Venice, arriving in the early afternoon after a 30-minute bus ride.  </p>
<p>
The weather was not great, being very overcast and a bit cool. We had about four hours to explore.  We walked to Piazza San Marco often getting bit lost, while stopping along the way to walk into an ancient church or to view a little canal. We were getting turned around because Google maps just not work well in a city of very narrow walking streets with four-story thick walled buildings looming on each side of the street. On the Riva next to San Marco, we finally purchased a city map.  Every other city will provide the visitor a map, but not in Venice.  The map was EXTREMELY useful.  As we were leaving Venice about 4 pm, the mist and the light rain began to fall. </p>
<p>
The next day, Friday, it rained ALL day long.  We took the day off, trying to stay warm and catch up on the news of the world.  </p>
<p>
Finally Saturday was a beautiful, warm, sunny day.  We covered some of the same ground that we did on Wednesday.  But we made it to several new parts of the old city.  At the end of the day at 5:00 pm, we returned to the Church of San Rocco.  Here we were greeted to an hour-long concert of organ, trumpet and a soprano. </p>
<p>
On Sunday, we left the Mestre Station for a ride lasting a bit over one hour.  We stopped in Verona, Where we will spend a week and which I will write more about next time.   </p>
\<p align='center' >
<b>Gondola on the Riva</b><br/>
<img alt='Gondola on the Riva IMG_0927'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5536/30367858246_decda0aa5d_c.jpg'   width='800' height='533' /></p>]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Trieste, Italy</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000256.html" />
    <modified>2016-10-12T17:40:57Z</modified>
    <issued>2016-10-12T12:40:57-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2016://1.256</id>
    <created>2016-10-12T17:40:57Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain"> Press HERE to see a slideshow of Trieste (50+ photos). Mr. Happy&apos;s Group - Alberto in Blue Plaid Shirt Trieste is an Austrian town in the north of Italy. How can that be? For 500 years it was part...</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    <dc:subject>Travel Journal</dc:subject>
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<div style='float: right; padding: 1em; margin-left: 6pt;'>
<p align='center'><b>Press <a href='https://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157675020902106/show/' target='_blank'>HERE</a> to see a slideshow<br/> of Trieste (50+ photos).</b></p>
</div>
<div style='float: left; padding: 1em; margin-right : 6pt;  '>
<p align='center'> <b>Mr. Happy's Group - Alberto in Blue Plaid Shirt</b> <br />
<iframe width="480" height="270" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dm5r69xdXs8" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
</div>
<p>
Trieste is an Austrian town in the north of Italy.  How can that be?  For 500 years it was part of the Hapsburg Empire.  The city was finally given to Italy in the early 1950's. The archetecture is dominated by 19th century Austrian styles.    </p>
<p>
We are couchsurfing here.  It has given a chance to really know our host Alberto Contento, also known as Mr. Happy.  He is an excellent singer. We have met several of his friends and some have become facebook friends.   </p>
<p>
While we are staying five nights, the weather has been far from perfect.  One day we stayed in due to cold, rain and wind.  One day we made it to the center, but quit roaming when the cold wind wore us out. We did take a LOT of pictures and we encouage you to see the slide show. </p>
<p>
Today we visited a mini-Versailles.  It was the House of Baron Pasquale Revoltella and the Revoltella Gallery of Modern Art.  The visit was wonderful.  </p>
<p>
Again, please, watch the slideshow.  Tomorrow we will be on our way to Venice.</p>
<p align='center' >
<b>Ships Preparing for the Barcolana Race</b><br/>
<img alt='Preparing for Barcolana IMG_0744'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5518/29652589103_c869a2e944_c.jpg'   width='800' height='450' /></p>
]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Ljubljana</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000255.html" />
    <modified>2016-10-07T10:34:25Z</modified>
    <issued>2016-10-07T05:34:25-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2016://1.255</id>
    <created>2016-10-07T10:34:25Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain"> Press HERE to see a slideshow of Ljubljana (50+ photos). Riverside from Cobbler&apos;s Bridge Dancers in Tivoli Park Ljubljana from the Castle Grounds Federico Del Vecchio with his Parents Ljubljana is the biggest city in one of the smallest...</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    <dc:subject>Travel Journal</dc:subject>
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<div style='float: right; padding: 1em; margin-left: 6pt;'>
<p align='center'><b>Press <a href='https://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157673586413872/show/' target='_blank'>HERE</a> to see a slideshow<br/> of Ljubljana (50+ photos).</b></p>
<table border = '0' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b>Riverside from Cobbler's Bridge</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8411/30167585365_d7fe2a6940_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Riverside from Cobblers Bridge IMG_0659'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8411/30167585365_d7fe2a6940_m.jpg'   width='260' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Dancers in Tivoli Park</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5233/30083160591_abd29e7b97_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Dancers in Tivoli Park IMG_0666'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5233/30083160591_abd29e7b97_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Ljubljana from the Castle Grounds</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5138/30083158081_dab401ae29_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Ljubljana from the Castle Grounds IMG_1436'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5138/30083158081_dab401ae29_m.jpg'   width='240' height='180'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Federico Del Vecchio with his Parents</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8129/30053176022_8c42c8b02f_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Federico Del Vecchio IMG_0686'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8129/30053176022_8c42c8b02f_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160' /> </a></td> </tr>


</tbody> </table>
</div><p>
Ljubljana is the biggest city in one of the smallest countries in Europe, Slovenia.  The city of 200,000 residents is one of the most beautiful cities in Europe.  We booked in for a week, which was a few days too many.  We rented a flat in <b>the best location</b> in the city, on the city's original main street.  This street and most of the most iconic streets in the city are paved with stones and are for pedestrians only. We paid a bit more for the location, but the apartment was near perfect for us.  The only snaffu was during our first two days when we had pretty disfunctional internet service. It is better now but still not up to an acceptable speed. </p>
<div style='float: left; padding: 1em; margin-right : 6pt;  '>
<table border = '0' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b> Lake Bled</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5525/29538841973_2ec79dddf7_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Lake Bled IMG_0701'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5525/29538841973_2ec79dddf7_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b>Betty and the Church on the Island</b> <br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5509/30083144431_49344e4379_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Betty and the Church IMG_0713'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5509/30083144431_49344e4379_m.jpg'   width='240' height='180'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b>Bled Castle and the Lake</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8549/30053165822_728486f568_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Bled Castle IMG_0716'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8549/30053165822_728486f568_m.jpg'   width='240' height='180'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b></b>Bled Mother's Group<br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8705/29538843133_6f7d945b5c_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Bled Mothers Group IMG_1466'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8705/29538843133_6f7d945b5c_m.jpg'   width='240' height='180'  /></a></td> </tr>
</tbody> </table>
</div>
<p>
So, we spent the first few days wandering the streets and squares of the city.  Several years ago they started banning traffic on many of the small streets in the city center.  We are living on the old main street of the city, Mestni, and there is only bicycle and pedestrian traffic.  Much of the archetecture comes from the work of Joze Plecnik.  My favorite pieces of his work are the triple bridge, the city market and the river embankments near the triple bridge.  </p>
<p>
One day we made our way to the high point of the city, the city castle.  The climb was very difficult as we are no longer spring chickens.  From the ramparts we found some beautiful views of the city.  Check out our slide show.  </p>
<p>
That same day we ate in very nice little restaurant whose name translates into  the Second Violin.  We sat at a table with strangers.  First was two students from England, both were Twainese.  They were just finishing up their degrees. One was moving back to Taiwan and the other not. When they were finished and we were still eating, Federico Del Vecchio and his parents asked if they could share our table.  Federico is an Italian art student at university here in Ljubljana.  He has studied and worked the world over. He told us this is the first time in 15 years his parents had been able to visit him where he was studying. We had a lovely conversation.  Betty loves seeing the building and chuches and I love the conversations.  We have both been getting what we like.  I've got to say, I love that English has become the international language.  Just about all travelers speak English.  And huge portions of the world population between the ages of 12 and 60 speak English.  And when you talk to those people you can learn so much. </p>
<p>
On Thursday we traveled to the town of Bled, a nice little town on the shore of lovely little lake.  In the lake is a small island where there is a large church.  The lake has path along the shore that is a bit more than two miles around.   About one-third the way round we stopped for coffee and a pastry.  Here we met the local sparrows as they flew by and looked for food at our feet and on the table.  At the adjoining table sat a half-dozen young mothers with four-month old children.  They had initially met in a Facebook group and now they meet regulary for mutual support.  We sat down with them to find out about the support system for Slovenian mothers.  First, their healthcare and the births were taken care by the Slovenian government.  One month before birth they begin a one-year maternity leave.  During the first three months they are paid 100% of the normal wages and for the nine-months after that 90% of the normal pay.  After one year of leave, they usually return to their jobs.  Through the government they can get infant child care for about $230 USD per month.  This is the sort of capitalism we need in the USA.      </p>
<p>
As we walked around the lake we met many fisherpeople, something we rarely see in Europe.  Lake Bled has a reputation for have very large carp, up to 70 pounds.  Most of the anglers were from Italy.  When I finally got to taking a photo of two fisherman, they were from the Czech Republic. The other thing I learned from them is that the fishing license for foreigners lasting <b>three</b> days is $165 USD.  They must be super dedicated fishermen.</p>
<p>
From Michael Moore's documentary, "Where to Invade Next," we learned that university tuition is free in Slovenia. From three different students we verified that all undergraduate university students pay no tuition.  By all I mean EVERYONE, including Americans.  This happens in a country of two million people.</p>
<p>
Today we are getting ready to leave on Saturday for Trieste. The stay has been quite pleasant, except for the irritation of a very unstable internet connection.  This is a VERY beautiful city with good and friendly people.  </p>

<p align='center' >
<b>Fountain at Center of Mestni Square</b><br/>
<img alt='Mestni Square IMG_0676'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5624/30132813046_c9cb6a94c2_c.jpg'   width='800' height='600' /></p>
]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Zagreb</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000254.html" />
    <modified>2016-09-30T10:11:58Z</modified>
    <issued>2016-09-30T05:11:58-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2016://1.254</id>
    <created>2016-09-30T10:11:58Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain"> Press HERE to see a slideshow of Zagreb (100+ photos). The Fountain in the Jelacic Square Sculpture at Ivan Mestrovic Atelier Varazdin Castle Before talking about our exploration of Zagreb, I want to start by saying what a wonderful...</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<div style='float: right; padding: 1em; margin-left: 6pt;'>
<p align='center'><b>Press <a href='https://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157671072770343/show/' target='_blank'>HERE</a> to see a slideshow<br/> of Zagreb (100+ photos).</b></p>
<table border = '0' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b> The Fountain in the  Jelacic Square</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8192/29961173845_f90dbe9740_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Fountain in the  Jelacic Square IMG_1309'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8192/29961173845_f90dbe9740_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Sculpture at Ivan Mestrovic Atelier</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8170/29334527813_6a7e4a37d6_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Sculpture at Ivan Mestrovic Atelier IMG_1333'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8170/29334527813_6a7e4a37d6_m.jpg'   width='240' height='180'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Varazdin Castle</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5312/29919452411_8c12c3b34a_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Varazdin Castle IMG_0642'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/6/5312/29919452411_8c12c3b34a_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>

</tbody> </table>
</div><p>
Before talking about our exploration of Zagreb, I want to start by saying what a wonderful city Zagreb is.  Zagreb is a city of about 900,000 people, which I think is a near perfect size.  The people are very friendly and extremely helpful to travelers.  Most of the people we met on the street could speak English.  It was great.  The public transit system is extensive.  No car is needed.  Buses and trams move the people around.  There were only two draw-backs, which are actually common to all of Croatia.  One, people smoke a lot and they smoke everywhere. Two, there is graffiti on the walls and fences of far too many buildings. </p>
<p>
We arrived by bus in Zagreb on the Wednesday, the 21st of September. We went to our first couchsurfing host in Croatia.  Marko is a very interesting man.  He left home at an early age and made a very good life for himself.  He has traveled to almost every country in the world.  He worked extensively in the UK and Ireland.  He was an app developer with an early success for an iPad app called Devolution.  We talked some and eventually took a bus to the city center.  Marko brought us to a restaurant to eat a Croatian specialty called "strukli."  It was a hot dish made of dough and salty cheese in a cream sauce.  The best of local comfort food.</p>
<p>
On Thursday we went to the old town and the information office.  In the office we got some great info about the city.  Besides a good map, we got a very good walking tour guide.  We would used it nearly everyday.  We started with the cathedral. and worked our way into the upper town, which is on a hill that looks down on the main square and the rest of the lower town.  I will let the pictures speak for our trekking through the town.  We made our way back to Marko's apartment to chat and pack, as we were going to stay with other hosts.    </p>
<div style='float: left; padding: 1em; margin-right : 6pt;  '>
<table border = '0' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b> Jo and Lucy's Favorite from Zabreb <br/>Public Scupture</b><br/>
    (laught out loud)<br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8577/29334586093_777a6f472d_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Public Pissing Scupture IMG_0590'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8577/29334586093_777a6f472d_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
</tbody> </table>
</div><p>
We stayed with two marvelous hosts, Ana and Dom, for the next two nights.  Ana speaks perfect English and Dom was nearly as good.  She teaches English and had lived for a year in California.  Dom works for Zagreb television.  They were incredibly kind and helpful.  Dom was instrumental in helping us find a small apartment.  While staying with them we continued our exploration of the old town of Zagreb.  Again I will let our pictures speak for us. </p>
Friday we visited two museums.  I really liked the Museum of Naive Art.  While developed in the 20th century, the pieces are very much like folk art and none the less just stunning. We also visited the studio  of the famous sculptor, Ivan Mestrovic.  His house and studio were beautiful and we took many photos. We were by St. Marks Church and that is were we saw the young man, Antoni, playing the Hang.  See my YouTube video to hear it. </p>
<p>
We booked for the first time on AirBnB.  We found a nice flat for $23 per day and booked it for a week.  It is on a bus route, so getting around is a breeze.  Bus fares are $1.60 each way.   </p>
<p>
Sunday we visited the cemetery. It is VERY large and has many interesting graves.  After this we did some wondering in the lower town only to return to the cathedral at 5:00 pm for a concert of of organ and trumpet music.  The trumpeter produced the most beautiful sounds.  The organ was built by the Walcher Company in 1855 and is a work of art in its sound and its vision.  Here are links to two recordings of what we heard.  This <a href='http://sundstrom.us/audio/ZagrebOrgan1.mp3' target='_blank' ><b>link</b></a> was my favorite piece.  And here is a  <a href='http://sundstrom.us/audio/ZagrebOrgan1.mp3' target='_blank' ><b>link</b></a> to other parts of the concert.  Please give a listen to them. </p>
<p>
Tuesday we visited two more museums:  The Gallery of Modern Art and The Museum of Arts and Crafts.  The modern art museum had a good representation of Croatian painters and sculptors of the past century and a half.  Some pieces were wonderful, others not so much.  For me the best part of the Arts and Crafts Museum was the furniture piece.  They gave me lots of ideas for things to make.  </p>
<div style='float: left; padding: 1em; margin-right : 6pt;  '>
<table border = '0' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b>Dom, Ana, Betty and Bill</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7696/29893566362_ece06c5c4b_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Dom,  Ana, Betty and Bill IMG_1411'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7696/29893566362_ece06c5c4b_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
</tbody> </table>
</div><p>
<p>
On Wednesday the 28th we rented a car for the day and drove to Varazdin. Varazdin is a lovely little town about 60 miles north of Zagreb known for its Baroque architecture.  We had lunch and walked about the town ending with a castle, which was once surrounded by a moat.  From Varazdin we drove to the Trackoscan Castle to take a look.  We returned to Zagreb just after dark, our phones dying before we got back to the rental office.  Thank goodness we brought a small GPS to use in the car.  </p>
<p>
The best part of Thursday was taking Dom and Ana out to lunch.  They are such a great couple and soon they will have their first child. We went to a recreational area on a lake within Zagreb to eat at a restaurant called Helena.  We are becoming friends. It was a really lovely afternoon.</p>
<p>
Now, we are getting ready for our next part of this journey.  We will leave for Ljubljana on tomorrow morning.  </p>

<p align='center' >
<b>View from Gradec</b><br/>
<img alt='View from Gradec IMG_0562'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8616/29961237245_5defbd4435_c.jpg'   width='800' height='533' /></p>

]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Plitvice Lakes National Park</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000253.html" />
    <modified>2016-09-21T08:27:54Z</modified>
    <issued>2016-09-21T03:27:54-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2016://1.253</id>
    <created>2016-09-21T08:27:54Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain"> This park is a true natural wonder of pools and lakes and thousands of cascades and falls. Our pictures will have to tell the story. Please, press HERE to see a slideshow of the park. There are a few...</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    <dc:subject>Travel Journal</dc:subject>
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<p>
This park is a true natural wonder of pools and lakes and thousands of cascades and falls. </p>
<p>
Our pictures will have to tell the story.  <b>Please, <a href='https://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157670825980954/show/' target='_blank'>press HERE</a> to see a slideshow of the park.</b> </p>
<p>
There are a few short videos to give you a better sense of the park and its sounds on my YouTube channel. The best one is at <a href='https://youtu.be/4jb1RKwwuXM' target='_blank'><b> this link</b></a>. </p>
<p>
<b>Please, <a href='https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCblceikAvst3KGK-sXPyNaQ' target='_blank'>press HERE</a> to go to my channel.<br/> </p>
<p align='center' >
<b>Bill and Betty at Plitvice Lakes</b><br/>
<img alt='Bill and Betty at Plitvice Lakes IMG_1300'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8334/29201260624_5774bab38a_c.jpg'   width='800' height='600' /></p>]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Split, Croatia</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000252.html" />
    <modified>2016-09-19T14:49:19Z</modified>
    <issued>2016-09-19T09:49:19-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2016://1.252</id>
    <created>2016-09-19T14:49:19Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain"> Press HERE to see a slideshow of Split, Croatia. Old Town Sight Sphinx of Diocletian On the Phone with Birgitta We got up at 4:30 in the morning on Thursday, the 15 of September. We had a ferry boat...</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    <dc:subject>Travel Journal</dc:subject>
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<div style='float: right; padding: 1em; margin-left: 6pt;'>
<p align='center'><b>Press <a href='https://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157672868236700/show/' target='_blank'>HERE</a> to see a slideshow<br/> of Split, Croatia.</b></p>
<table border = '0' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Old Town Sight</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8256/29750021406_f57af18825_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Old Town Sight IMG_0397'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8256/29750021406_f57af18825_m.jpg'   width='240' height='180'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Sphinx of Diocletian</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8160/29160532313_0e9bbee82f_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Sphinx of Diocletian IMG_0418'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8160/29160532313_0e9bbee82f_m.jpg'   width='240' height='135'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>On the Phone with Birgitta</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8389/29786024405_226a1ee163_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='On the phone  IMG_0459'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8389/29786024405_226a1ee163_m.jpg'   width='240' height='180'  /></a></td> </tr>

</tbody> </table>
</div>

<p>
We got up at 4:30 in the morning on Thursday, the 15 of September.  We had a ferry boat to get on before its 6:00 am departure.  We had packed the night before and had almost everything ready. After a shower, a bit of breakfast and coffee, we made our way to the east side pier in Korcula. The catamaran ferry left on time and delivered us to Split some four hours later.  </p>

<div style='float: left; padding: 1em; margin-right : 6pt;  '>
<table border = '0' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>The Romans of Split</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8102/29750005996_7f83fb5c19_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Romans of Split IMG_1238'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8102/29750005996_7f83fb5c19_n.jpg'   width='240' height='300'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Trogir's Harbor</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8565/29673411082_9e07d4823b_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Trogirs Harbor IMG_0465'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8565/29673411082_9e07d4823b_m.jpg'   width='240' height='135'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Boys in Trogir</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8530/29750002006_ea037ddb5f_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Trogirs Harbor IMG_1264'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8530/29750002006_ea037ddb5f_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
</tbody> </table>
</div>
<p>
We hiked a mile to an address that someone sent me for an apartment rental.  The manager was not there but a neighbor got him on the phone and soon he was there.  We could not have that apartment.  A pity as it was quite nice.  But he did have a room with a shared kitchen for us on the other side of the old town.  It was suppose to have internet and it did for the first two days.  Our so called free 3-g service from t-mobile does not work worth a damn is Split.  I called t-mobile to see if we could buy a fast data stream. If I understood them correctly, they want $25 for 1/2 a gig that would last only one week.  This is an insanely high price.  So, I had to say forget it.   </p><p>
Well, anyway we found a place to rest our heads at night and we did get a couple of days of internet.  We will be moving on as soon as possible.  We explored a bit of the city on Thursday.  The big draw to Split is the Dioclitian's Palace, which was the retirement home of the Roman Emperor Dioclitian.  At one time about 300 AD the temple was the city.  As time passed the city expanded and as the temple began to wear, parts of it were superseded by new structure.  Still, much of the original structure is still there.  We spent most of Friday trying to explore every last bit of it.  </p>
<p>
Saturday started a bit on a sour note, but by the time it was over Saturday was one of best days in Croatia.  The sour notes were in the morning when it rained and the internet in our rooms ended. But that was the morning.</p>
<p>
By noon on Saturday we were on the move.  We walked to the the docks in the city center.  We boarded a public transport boat to cross the huge bay and go to the the town of Trogir. The boat passage was about one hour with only one stop along the way.  Trogir is a very small town on a very small island.  The island sits between the mainland and a very large island, and all are connected by bridges.  We spent several hours exploring the town and its old buildings. </p>
<p>
As the afternoon came to a close, we got on a bus that was headed back to Split.  We got off the bus at Kastel Stari about half-way to Split.  We met up with a wonderful German couple from Bremman that we met at concert in Korcula. Their names are Christian and Anneke Garst.  We shared an excellent meal in the open are on the coast of the Adriatic Sea.  We shared stories of our lives, our former jobs, our children and grandchildren.  On the way back to Split I told Betty what a delightful day it was for us. </p>
<p> 
Our last two days were not very eventful.  We arranged to move to a room with internet.  We went into the old city to hang our and drink a coffee.  Last night Betty cooked a great dinner.  They say it is unusual for this time of the year, but there was a big thunderstrom last night. And there was a good rain this afternoon.    </p>
<p>
Tomorrow we will travel to the Plitvice Lakes National Park and the day after that to Zagreb. Be sure to click the slide show link for more photos of Split and Trogir, Croatia.  </p>
<p align='center' >
<b>Bill with Chris and Anneke Garst </b><br/>
<img alt='Korcula IMG_1203'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8235/29673407042_0dc83aba8f_c.jpg'   width='800' height='450' /></p>]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Korcula</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000251.html" />
    <modified>2016-09-14T15:31:09Z</modified>
    <issued>2016-09-14T10:31:09-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2016://1.251</id>
    <created>2016-09-14T15:31:09Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain"> Press HERE to see a slideshow of Korcula. West Pier in Korcula With Joseph &quot;Bire&quot; Milina Swimmers in Korcula Vineyard Outside Kneza Wind Surfers Korcula is pronounced &quot;KOR-choo-la.&quot; Kocula is both the name of a town and the island...</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    <dc:subject>Travel Journal</dc:subject>
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<div style='float: right; padding: 1em; margin-left: 6pt;'>
<p align='center'><b>Press <a href='https://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157670531677023/show/' target='_blank'>HERE</a> to see a slideshow<br/> of Korcula.</b></p>
<table border = '0' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>West Pier in Korcula</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8548/29026601284_a2f48720dc_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='West Pier in Korcula IMG_6316'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8548/29026601284_a2f48720dc_m.jpg'   width='240' height='135'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>With Joseph "Bire" Milina</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8411/29653027525_5bd11f3661_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='With Joseph Milina IMG_6327'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8411/29653027525_5bd11f3661_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Swimmers in Korcula</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8407/29571622341_55c0e665a2_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Swimmers IMG_6338'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8407/29571622341_55c0e665a2_m.jpg'   width='240' height='135'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Vineyard Outside Kneza</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8502/29617716566_a8e9f90b57_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Kneza Vineyard IMG_6343'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8502/29617716566_a8e9f90b57_m.jpg'   width='240' height='135'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Wind Surfers</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8091/29544176312_05501c6916_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Wind Surfers IMG_6346'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8091/29544176312_05501c6916_m.jpg'   width='240' height='135'  /></a></td> </tr>
</tbody> </table>
</div>
<p>
   Korcula is pronounced "KOR-choo-la." Kocula is both the name of a town and the island it is on.  It has a very sleepy existence except for a good number of tourist that come every summer.  The town has a beautiful old city that takes less than 35 minutes to circle on foot. We came to the town by bus from Dubrovnik last Friday.  We were greeted by Marina who had a very small apartment for rent.  She showed us the flat and negotiated a price for first three days and later another three days.  The total cost for the six days was about $210 dollars.  Marina and her husband Joseph manage the <a href='https://www.facebook.com/likemekorcula1/' target='_blank' >Hostel Korcula Caenazzo</a>. 
They are very kind and likable.   </p>
<p>
We started by exploring the old city.  We have been to concerts for the Korcula Baroque Festival.  The first one was on Saturday. It was the Baroque Opera "Dido and Aeneas" by Henry Purcell and sung in English.  The outdoor concert was interrupted for a few minutes twice as light rain came down. Still it was a very nice concert and you can hear a few minutes of it at this <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=f_8abiYS-nw' target='_blank' >link</a>.    </p>
<p>
On Sunday we walked to the nearby village of Lumbarda.  It is about 5 kilometers from Korcula. We are getting use to the walking, but we were glad to accept a lift from a passing driver when we were about half way to the town.  Our first stop was the Bire winery.  Bire and the other local wineries are the only producers of the fine white variety called <b>"grk"</b>.  Bire is the only winery that is closed on Sunday.  Luckily the owner's 18 year-old son, Joseph, let us in to taste the very good wine.  We left with a bottle to drink later.  From Bire we walked to the harbor, and around the beaches and then to another winery to taste a bit more of the <b>grk</b> wine.  After a couple of hours we started walking back to Korcula.  Since we were lucky to be offered a ride part way to Lumbarda, we decided to try hitch-hiking back to Korcula.  The success was not immediate, but we eventually got a lift back. We were very tired upon our return.  Thanks to our activity bands, we know that we walked more than five miles on Sunday. </p>
<p>
I want to mention two things here.  The beaches are not sandy, rather they have small smooth stones that are not uncomfortable to walk on.  The beaches are numberous and quite small.  The draw here is the water.  I have never before seen such CRYSTAL clear water in a salt water sea. Everytime I look into the water, I feel awed.  Stepping into it, I discovered that it as warm as a Minnesota lake in the summer.    </p>
<p>
Second, I want to mention that I first hitch-hiked at the age of seven, going two miles to the Oxboro center.  As I grew older, it became one of my main forms of transportation.  I hitched all over the USA and Europe back in the 1960's.  But I finally got a car in the 1970's and did little or no hitching since then. But the lastest round of hitching means that I have been at it more than 60 years. There are so few hitch-hikers today.  I wish there were more. There should be, after all they call it a sharing economy.</p>
<div style='float: left; padding: 1em; margin-right : 6pt;  '>
<p align='center'> <b>Duo Sol</b> <br />
<iframe width="480" height="270" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/_FUC-GVzg7c" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>
</div>
<p>
On Monday, I wanted to see two other smaller villages along the north coast of island.  We walked a mile out of the town along the road leading to Kneza and Recisce, some 15 kilometers to the west.  We could never hike that far, so we began hitch-hiking and we soon had a lift to Recisce.  We waded in the sea and soaked up the atmosphere of this little village.  We had a meal of fried fish with vegtables and beer.  We began walking back to Kneza, a short cut up hill and it took about 40 minutes to hike there.  Along the way we got a call from Birgitta.  We have been using Viber to talk to her.  It is a really fine VOIP app that lets you talk to friends and family on the data network, which we get free as part of our t-mobile phone plan.  Anyway, we were soon in the village and decided to try hitching back to Korcula.  After a half-hour or so, a very nice French couple picked us up and brought us to Korcula.  We had a drink with them, sharing stories of our lives and our children.  It was very nice.  On Monday we only walked 4-1/2 miles.   </p>
<p>
We had a very quite day yesterday, Tuesday.  We washed our clothes. Did some shopping. Betty fried chicken for dinner.  In the evening we went to a really amazing concert.  The Royal Wind Music performed a concert of Baroque recorder music.  There were 13 muscians playing dozens of recorders of different sizes from less than 12 inches long to 8 feet tall. I have never heard such a group before.  You can hear their first piece at this <a href='https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=koujgEWwqho' target='_blank' >link</a>. </p>
<p>
I embeded another youTube video on this page.  On Saturday we heard two local folk musician playing at a wedding reception. Later I saw them singing at the city gate. Ante Petkovic plays the accordion and Drazen Burazer is playing guitar.  The song was interrupted for a bit as Drazen sold a CD.  During the interruption, an unknown tourist joined Ante in singing the Croatian folk song.   </p>
<p>
We leave early in the morning of a ferry to Split, Croatia.   </p>
<p align='center' >
<b>View of Korcula's Old City </b><br/>
<img alt='Korcula IMG_1203'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8801/29653055885_28b11c11b1_c.jpg'   width='800' height='450' /></p>
]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Dubrovnik</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000250.html" />
    <modified>2016-09-10T16:53:33Z</modified>
    <issued>2016-09-10T11:53:33-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2016://1.250</id>
    <created>2016-09-10T16:53:33Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain"> Press HERE to see a slideshow of Dubrovnik. Bill by the Fortress Sword Play Betty at Onofrio&apos;s Foutain It has been quite some time since my last entry. I almost forgot how to set up the pictures. But it...</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    <dc:subject>Travel Journal</dc:subject>
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<div style='float: right; padding: 1em; margin-left: 6pt;'>
<p align='center'><b>Press <a href='https://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157673661613355/show/'>HERE</a> to see a slideshow<br/> of Dubrovnik.</b></p>
<table border = '0' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Bill by the Fortress</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8319/29461907512_852937e394_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Bill by the Fortress<'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8319/29461907512_852937e394_m.jpg'   width='240' height='135'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Sword Play</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7568/29537614976_3d10441161_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='IMG_1153: Sword Play'  src='https://c2.staticflickr.com/8/7568/29537614976_3d10441161_m.jpg'   width='240' height='160'  /></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b> <br/>Betty at Onofrio's Foutain</b><br/>
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8283/29281554310_823ea6f9e9_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='IMG_0334: Betty at Onofrio Fountain'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8283/29281554310_823ea6f9e9_m.jpg'   width='240' height='180'  /></a></td> </tr>
</tbody> </table>
</div>
<p>
It has been quite some time since my last entry.  I almost forgot how to set up the pictures.  But it is slowly coming back to me.  I hope this entry will be enoyable.   </p>
<p>
We flew to Dubrovnik on <a href='https://www.condor.com/us/index.jsp' target='_blank' >Condor</a>. The one-way tickets were under $500 each.  Condor, a subsidary of Lufthansa, brought us to Frankfort on a fairly uncomfortable flight.  Uncomfortable because the seat are way too close together. I think they were as bad as our national flights on Spirit Airlines.  My only saving grace was that the seats behind us were unfilled, so I figured out how to lie on them. And I acutally got some sleep.  The second leg was on the Croatian Airlines, which, although being an hour late, was a very nice flight with great snacks (olives and cheese) and a glass of wine.  We had arrived at the airport in Minneapolis around 5:00 pm on Labor Day and arrived some 18 hours later around 7:00 pm at our room in Dubrovnik. </p>
<div style='float: left; padding: 1em; margin-right : 6pt;  '>
<p align='center'> <b> Our Dubrovnik Selfie</b> <br />
	<a href='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8617/29537607736_47371ac560_b.jpg' target='_blank' >
	<img alt='Our Selfie'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8617/29537607736_47371ac560_n.jpg'   width='320' height='213'  /></a></p>
<p align='center'> <b> Dubrovnik Guitar Trio</b> <br />
<iframe width="320" height="160" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/h1ox27xZ4Ss" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</p>
</div>
<p>
Accommodations in Dubrovnik are quite dear.  There are no couchsurfing hosts. Our room was quite small and in a house where we shared a bath with another couple.  Because we booked in the US the cost was over $70 per day.  Had we been able to book directly with the owner, the cost would have been $50 per night.  Needless to say accommodations are quite expensive here as is everything else, save beer and wine.   </p>
<p>
We could not get to sleep until almost midnight.  Remember when it's midnght here, it's 5:00 pm in the middle of the USA.  Needless to say our internal time clocks have been messed up for the last five days.  </p>
<p>
There must be millions that come to the old city every year. Even with the tourist season winding down, thousands filled the streets and alleys everyday. One reason it has become even more popular in recent years has to do with the TV show "The Game of Thrones."  Many of the scenes from the show were filmed in Dubrovnik. It is a very old city with a well preserved  medieval appearance.  The old city has only one street that a car or small truck can get into for deliveries in the early morning.  How they get in and out is a mystery to me, but I saw delivery trucks before 9:00 am one morning.      </p>
<p>
We did not do all the regular tourist things in Dubrovnik. We did not walk atop the city walls.  We found little nooks to sit and enjoy the surroundings.  For example, we found area just outside the city wall by the Lovrijenac Fortress to be very peaceful. And we liked the old port on the south side of the old city. The weather was good most of the time with just one morning with mist and light rain.    </p>
<p>
The third day after arriving, on our last evening we went out to for dinner. <a href='https://www.facebook.com/LADY.PI.PI.Dubrovnik/' target='_blank'>Lady Pi-Pi</a> Restaurant was very good and not overly expensive. We both ordered the goulash, which Americans would call beef stew.  It was excellent.  After dinner we attended a classical guitar concert in the Rector's Palace Atrium.  The music was delightful.  In some of the pieces the guitar trio was accompanied by a mezzo-soprano.  </p>
<p>
On Friday, the 9th we got on a bus to Korcula, the name of both a town and an island.  We will stay here until at least Monday and maybe beyond.   </p>
<p>
   </p>
<p>
   </p>
<p align='center' >
<b>View of the Dubrovnik's Old City </b><br/>
<img alt='Old City of Dubrovnik Img_0342'  src='https://c1.staticflickr.com/9/8772/29491073601_7678d899e9_c.jpg'   width='800' height='534' /></p>   ]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>Our Winter in Sun City</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000249.html" />
    <modified>2015-05-03T03:57:38Z</modified>
    <issued>2015-05-02T22:57:38-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2015://1.249</id>
    <created>2015-05-03T03:57:38Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain"> Betty and I headed for Arizona the first week of January. It was -15 degrees when we left MN. We drove south and it did not get above zero until we had travelled through three states. Two days later...</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    <dc:subject>Travel Journal</dc:subject>
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<p>
Betty and I headed for Arizona the first week of January.  It was -15 degrees when we left MN.  We drove south and it did not get above zero until we had travelled through three states.  Two days later when we arrived in Sun City, it was in the 70's.  And that is why we head south in the winter.   The weather has been spectacular, mostly sun and warmth.  Yes, it rained a few days, but nothing to cry about. </p>

<div style='float: right; padding: 1em; margin-left : 6pt;  '>
<table border = '1' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b>Carport</b> <br/>
	Click to see whole house<br/>
	<a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157652315870401/show/' target="_blank" >
	<img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8777/17159551630_1d96b12bf3_m.jpg" width="240" height="180" alt="Carport"></a></td> </tr>
</td>
<td> <b>Centerpiece Candleholder</b> <br/>
	<a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157651903980739/show/' target="_blank" >
	<img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8762/17158915950_1afce4533a_m.jpg" width="240" height="135" alt="Candleholder"></a></br>
	Click to see other projects<br/>
	</td> </tr>
</td>
<td> <b>Bill, Lise, Daisy and Betty</b> <br/>
	<a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157649997912133/show/' target="_blank" >
	<img src="https://farm9.staticflickr.com/8778/17345240842_a888338384_m.jpg" width="240" height="135" alt="Bill, Lise, Daisy and Betty"></a></br>
	Click to see LOTS of pics<br/>
	</td> </tr>
</td>
<td> <b>Gambel's Quail</b> <br/>
	<a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157651862493077/show/' target="_blank" >
	<img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7661/17321147666_1e5dc0f578_m.jpg" width="240" height="135" alt="IMG_6214: Gambel's Quail"></a></br>
	Click to see animals<br/>
	</td> </tr>
</td>
	</tbody> </table>
</div>
<p>
So, why Sun City?  Betty seems to think it is some sort of Eden.  It is fairly low cost.  Sun City has a lot to do.  You join the recreation centers, where one can find almost every kind of activity.  I am not going to itemize them, but I would like to mention what we have done.  We took bridge lessons and played bridge at one of the dozen bridge clubs.  Betty joined a 500 (card) club.  I joined one of the three woodworking clubs. I went bowling.  We played pool.  We played tennis several days per week.  Betty took swim lessons and finally learned to swim.  She also took a water aerobics class. There are three rec centers within one mile of our rental, and I like to walk to them.</p>


<p>
Here is some info on our rental.  This is a twin home with a 1800 sf unit.  We paid $1350 per month which included everything.  The normal rent on this place is $1500 to $1800 per month on a four-month basis.  There are two bedrooms and two baths.  There is a formal dining area connected to the living room.  There is also an Arizona room, a room that might have once been a large enclosed porch - but is now an extension of the living room.  There is a large decorative orange tree out front, and huge grapefruit tree in the back.  There was a ton of fruit on the tree when we arrived.  I drank juice almost every day and we often had grapefruit Margaritas.  What a refreshing drink that is.  The owner bought it a little over 18 months ago for $90 K, furnished, and has not had to do anything to it.  It is full of 1970's things - especially in the kitchen.  </p>
<p>
I built a lot of small projects in the wood shop.  I made three end-grain cutting boards for Birgitta, Dain and our house.   I made a garden bench as a test project, then gave it to Dain and Marleta. I made some very nice centerpiece candleholders.  I learned how to make small wooden boxes.   I really enjoyed the workshop, and I spent a lot of days making things.    </p>
<p>
All the rec centers have pools where we swam and mini-golf courses.  In two of the rec centers, there are county library branches.   </p>
<p>
You can buy a house for $80 to $250k with most homes going for about $110k.  Rentals for a couple of months are close to $2000 per month but $1000 or less for six months or more.   </p>
<p>
We had several visitors.  My brother Brian and his wife Judy stayed nearby for about two and a half weeks.  My brother Steve and his wife Ellen came and stayed with us for a week.  Our old friend Lise Nicholson of Alberta visited a friend of hers in Sun City West and we hung out with them a lot.  We were hoping for more visitors but maybe they will come next year.  </p>
<p>
Yes, we are coming back next year.  I am not wild about the idea, but it is a done deal. Betty has signed a lease for a bigger and yet less expensive rental.   </p>
<p>
The most abundant form of wildlife in the area is the grouse.  They are everywhere.  Next up is a little bunny.  There are all kinds of other birds.  In the morning and evening they are all singing.  The cacophonous sound is wonderful   We hear there are coyotes all about, but we have not seen one.   We have seen lizards, a tortoise and a blue heron.</p>
<p>
Well that's it.  We are headed north tomorrow.    </p>
<p>
By the way, we drove to Palo Alto for Easter.  There is a set of pictures from the Facebook campus and its new mega-building with the living roof. See the set at<b>
<a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157652255936396/show/' target="_blank" >this link</a>.</b> John, Matt, and Susan came over for one of Betty's scrumptous Easter hams.  It was great to visit with them and to stay with Dain and Marleta.   </p>
]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>
  <entry>
    <title>April in Cuernavaca</title>
    <link rel="alternate" type="text/html" href="http://bill.sundstrom.us/archives/000248.html" />
    <modified>2014-04-30T18:43:47Z</modified>
    <issued>2014-04-30T13:43:47-06:00</issued>
    <id>tag:bill.sundstrom.us,2014://1.248</id>
    <created>2014-04-30T18:43:47Z</created>
    <summary type="text/plain"> Press HERE to see a new slideshow from Cuernavaca. Peacock in Full Color Strutting Peacock and Betty View of the Roman Garden Entrance to Cactus Garden The first week in April was all about Betty&apos;s birthday. She has gotten...</summary>
    <author>
      <name>bill</name>
      <url>http://bill.sundstrom.us</url>
      <email>bill@sundstrom.us</email>
    </author>
    <dc:subject>Travel Journal</dc:subject>
    <content type="text/html" mode="escaped" xml:lang="en" xml:base="http://bill.sundstrom.us/">
      <![CDATA[<div style='float: right; padding: 1em; margin-left : 6pt;  '>
<p align='center'><b>Press <a href='http://www.flickr.com/photos/bill_sundstrom/sets/72157642168396783/show/' target="_blank" >HERE</a> to see a new slideshow<br/> from Cuernavaca.</b> </p>
<table border = '1' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b>Peacock in Full Color</b><br/>
	<a href='https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3779/13763777544_8055abc5c8_b.jpg'>
	<img src="https://farm4.staticflickr.com/3779/13763777544_8055abc5c8_m.jpg" width="240" height="180" alt="IMG_5909: Peacock"></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b>Strutting Peacock and Betty</b><br/>
	<a href='https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7233/13763853044_0fcac08e02_b.jpg'>
	<img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7233/13763853044_0fcac08e02_m.jpg" width="240" height="135" alt="IMG_0337 Strutting Cock"></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b>View of the Roman Garden</b><br/>
	<a href='https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7242/13763345055_201e83c5a5_b.jpg'>
	<img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7242/13763345055_201e83c5a5_m.jpg" width="240" height="160" alt="IMG_5939 Roman Garden"></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td><b>Entrance to Cactus Garden</b><br/>
	<a href='https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2863/13763326085_bdecdae3a9_b.jpg'>
	<img src="https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2863/13763326085_bdecdae3a9_m.jpg" width="240" height="160" alt="IMG_5948: Cactus Garden"></a></td> </tr>
	</tbody> </table>
</div>

<p>
The first week in April was all about Betty's birthday.  She has gotten old enough to go on Medicare, and as her spouse I will get to join her.  Trouble is, she does not know what to do yet. </p>

<div style='float: left; padding: 1em; margin-right : 6pt;  '>
<table border = '1' >
<tbody align='center'>
<tr>
<td> <b>Lunch by the Zocolo</b><br/>
	<a href='https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2918/14066226492_7dd3664483_b.jpg'>
	<img src="https://farm3.staticflickr.com/2918/14066226492_7dd3664483_m.jpg" width="240" height="180" alt="IMG_0401: Lunch"></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b>Club de Golf Los Tabachines</b><br/>
	<a href='https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5152/14069395425_f2af8e5f75_b.jpg'>
	<img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5152/14069395425_f2af8e5f75_m.jpg" width="240" height="160" alt="IMG_0411: Club de Golf Los Tabachines"></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b>Wall of Seed Art</b><br/>
	<a href='https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7383/14089460853_d29dd57028_b.jpg'>
	<img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7383/14089460853_d29dd57028_m.jpg" width="240" height="180" alt="IMG_5955: Wall of Seeds"></a></td> </tr>
<tr>
<td> <b>Quesadilla Maker</b><br/>
	<a href='https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7210/14046292056_6704ac5277_b.jpg'>
	<img src="https://farm8.staticflickr.com/7210/14046292056_6704ac5277_m.jpg" width="240" height="180" alt="IMG_5959: She Made me a Quesadilla"></a></td> </tr>
	</tbody> </table>
</div>
<p>
We celebrated one night by visiting the oldest restaurant in Cuernavaca, <a href='http://www.laindiabonita.com.mx/index.html' target="_blank">La India Bonita</a>.  It was once the mansion of Dwight Morrow. a former US Ambassador to Mexico. 
On the night of her birthday we went to the well known <a href='http://www.lasmananitas.com.mx/' target="_blank">Las Mañanitas</a>.  They have a piano bar, and restaurant seating that over looks a beautiful garden.  In the garden there are peacocks, and rather large and colorful parrots. When the peacocks opened their feathers, it was quite a beautiful sight. </p>
<p>
The very next day we visited <a href='http://jardinesdemexico.com/' target="_blank">Jardines de Mexico</A>.  The gardens are very beautiful.  They finished the construction and had the inauguration ceremonies around the first of April.  We were there on the ninth and everything was completed except the scent greenhouse.  We were impressed.  They were not as great as the Butchart Gardens in British Columbia; still it was very impressive.  The gardens are about 35 miles south of Cuernavaca and one could easily miss the turn off to them.  The best part of the gardens is the cactus display. </p>
<p>
But really,  we have mostly been taking it very easy: walking to the city center once a week, swimming a couple of days every week,  and the dinner out from time to time.  The best of the dinners out are the occasional Saturday night dinners with Jim and Jane.    Jim is our landlord and Jane rents another of Jim's apartments.   We have done some pretty fine dining with them.  One the best was Easter Brunch at Club de Golf los Tabachines.  The view from the restaurant balcony was stunning and the food was very good.  By the way, the tabachine tree is in flower right now.  Its super orange flowers make a spectacular vision. </p>
<p>
Speaking of neighbors.  A French couple moved into the apartment above us.  They have three-month old twin girls.  They have been here all month waiting to get documents from both the French and Mexican governments, so they can bring their girls home. He is a fine artist and is creating a children's book. </p>
<p>
Last Sunday, we visited Tepoztlan.  It was once a sleepy little village 10 miles east of Cuernavaca.  Today it is quite the tourist attraction for their artisan markets on Wednesday and Sunday.  We went to see the art and get souvenirs for Joey and Lucy.  We succeeded in our goal and bought a number of items for them. </p>
<p>
We are headed north tomorrow.  It takes several days to get to the northland.  We are not excited about returning to cold and maybe snowy weather that has persisted in the northland.  But we will be so happy to see Johanna, Lucy and Birgitta.</p>

<p align='center'><b>White Peacocks in Full Feather</b><br />
<a href='https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5287/13763485505_5f1333635f_b.jpg'>
<img src="https://farm6.staticflickr.com/5287/13763485505_5f1333635f_c.jpg" width="800" height="449" alt="IMG_0341 Peacock"></a></p>
]]>
      
    </content>
  </entry>

</feed>